Hello and welcome to the P&P Certification
Complete video course.
My name is Asad Hauck and
I'm the founder and owner of
First Choice Project Management
Training based in Chicago.
I've been teaching PMP
since 2010, the year I turned my
PMP certificate and back
then it was based on PIMBock 4.
Over the years I've become
well versed with all the exam
changes through to the
current exam content outline.
So I totally understand what you are going
through right now with all this studying.
I've been there myself.
My background has primarily been in the IT
world and mostly HRS consulting,
but also in finance and accounting and
regulatory compliance.
After 20 plus years as an IT professional,
I decided to move into the training side
of things and really to teach people how
to manage projects properly after
experiencing so many inefficiencies and
management failures over the years.
In addition to PMP, I also teach
fundamentals of project management,
facilitate leadership and strategic
business management training, and develop
training curriculum for corporations,
including this one, which I developed for
Pearson with the assistance of my fellow
PMP instructor here, Kimberly Casperson.
Hi, I'm Kimberly Casperson PMP.
I'm the CEO and owner
of KJC Consulting and PM
Training LLC, a veteran and
woman-owned small business.
I am an adjunct instructor to universities
and have been instructing PMP prep classes
full-time working on small projects on the
side since November 2012.
My background includes over 11 years of
training, as well as over 20 years of
project management and consulting in a
variety of industries including
healthcare, marketing, biopharmaceutical
research, and construction services.
I am a U.S.
Air Force veteran, voice processor,
career.
and linguist and have
worked for the Department of
Defense and the state of Ohio's
Department of Development.
The primary purpose of this video course
is to teach you how to pass the PMP exam.
This course will lead you through the
topics you need to know as well as
pointers on how to navigate through the
ambiguous PMP exam questions.
It will be important for you to study the
lessons and flashcards plus take those
simulated exams that are
provided to fully prepare
can't tell you how important
those simulated exams are.
The PMP exam changed in January 2021 and
one of the major changes was that 50% of
the exam is now based
on agile and hybrid concepts
and 50% on traditional
predictive principles.
Agile and predictive are two conflicting
styles of project management but
understanding both of these styles is now
required by PMI.
This complete video course will lead you
through all the concepts of predictive and
agile, plus the older new topics that you
need to know, as well as exam technique.
Success, however, is
going to depend on you, the
candidate, having the
right approach to studying.
And this is what we will start off with in
lesson one getting prepared for the exam.
Here we introduce you to the
format of the exam, the types
of questions you will encounter,
as well as some exam tips.
We will continue on to lesson two learning
foundational concepts which discusses the
basic definitions and terminology that we
build on in subsequent lessons.
In all lessons, we will discuss both
predictive and agile concepts.
In lesson three, project integration
management, I'll discuss how the project
manager integrates the planning,
executing, and monitoring activities to
lead project teams through the project,
from beginning to end.
In Lesson 4, Project Scope Management,
I will cover the importance of collecting
a good set of requirements, creating a
scope statement and the work breakdown
structure to understand the work necessary
to complete the project.
Project Schedule Management covers
estimating duration using various
estimating tools for both predictive and
agile environments.
Because this is a large topic area,
it has been broken down into two lessons,
Lesson 5 and Lesson 6.
In Lesson 7, I will be covering cost
management, which includes estimating
costs on the project and developing the
budget.
One of the key success factors of a
project is having a good quality
management process, and that is a topic of
discussion in Lesson
8, Quality Management.
Here I will talk about the importance of
the various quality tools and the
differences between quality assurance and
quality control.
Now, you cannot perform a project without
a team.
Project Resource Management
discusses a management
of physical and team
resources on a project.
Project Resource Management is another
huge topic, and again, it has been broken
down into two lessons, lesson nine and
lesson 10.
In these lessons, I will discuss the
different roles on a project and introduce
new leadership topics that have been added
for the new exam.
In lesson 11, Project Communication
Management, I'll explain
the importance of communication
throughout the project and
discuss some of the
tools that we will use.
Lesson 12, project risk management is
another area of critical focus for a
project manager because risks impact every
area of a project.
In this lesson, I will talk about planning
risks, analyzing risks
and responding to risks.
Many projects require resources from
outside of the organization, such as
equipment, materials, consultants and
contractors.
I will discuss the management of these
external resources in Lesson 13,
Project Resource Management.
Last is Lesson 14, Project Stakeholder
Management, which I discussed the
importance of identifying and engaging our
stakeholders, leading to project success.
In addition to these videos,
it is again important for you
to take practice exams as part
of this complete video course.
You have access to quizzes and simulated
exams, and you will need to take these.
simulated exams in order to practice exam
technique.
We also highly recommend that you download
a copy of PIMBOC version 6 and the Agile
Practice Guide and use these as a
reference throughout your studies.
If you're a member of PMI or you can
download these guides for free from the pm
.i.org website, but you do have to be a
member in order to get these for free.
The Agile Practice
Guide is appended at the
end of the PIMBOC guide when downloaded.
Even though this will be a very intensive
training course.
Kimberly and I hope you all enjoy the
class.
So let's get started.